英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with Day 2 for the month of October.
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Suresi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今月は食や料理をテーマに学習しています。
そして今回のキーワードは
MAKE
動詞のMAKEは料理について話すときに広く使えます。
便利な動詞ですよ。
では、
一緒に練習して使いこなせるようになりましょう。
一回目の挑戦です。
It's time for your first try.
F.P.R. Training
では僕の言う日本語を時間内に英語で表現してください。
一つ目はこちら。
朝食にオムレツを作りました。
では次です。
まずこれを英語で言ってみましょう。
チャーハン
答えを言います。
Stir-fried rice
スターフライドライスを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
昼食にチャーハンを作りました。
Good
次はこちらです。
デザートにパンプキンパイを焼きました
答えを言います
I made a pumpkin pie for dessert
I baked a pumpkin pie for dessertも通じますが
メイクを使うことが一般的です
さあ次の文です
まだ夕食は何も作っていません
では次行きましょう。まずこれを英語で言ってください。アイルランド料理。答えはアイリッシュディッシュ。それを使ってこちらを言いましょう。アイルランド料理を作りました。
では次です。これはシェパーズパイと言います。
さあ、次はこの少し長いクエスチョンを英語で言ってみよう。
こちら。
アイルランドでは普段家でシェパードズパイを作りますか?
In Ireland, do people usually…
彼、言ってください。
どうぞ。
さあ、次はハロウィンについての文を言ってみよう。
ハロウィンに家族でお寿司屋さんに行きました。
Our family went.
彼行ってください。
どうぞ。
では次です。
まず英語で回転寿司を言ってみましょう。
どうぞ。
決まった言い方はないんですがこれはよく聞きます。
Conveyor belt sushi.
では、それを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
回転寿司のお店に行きました。
さあ、次の文はまたハロウィンについてです。
ハロウィンをテーマにしたお寿司がありました。
Tokidoki, iede, osushi wo tsukurimasu.
Okay, how was your first round?
Did you try to say each one?
Dewa, koko de kaitou rei wo chekishimashou.
Now you can check your answers with mine.
And if you have our textbook, you can open it up and follow along.
Listen closely.
朝食にオムレツを作りました。
I made an omelette for breakfast.
単数形の場合は、omelette。
複数形は、I made omelettes for breakfast.
さあ、次です。
昼食にチャーハンを作りました。
I made stir-fried rice for lunch.
デザートにパンプキンパイを焼きました。
I made a pumpkin pie for dessert.
まだ夕食は何も作っていません。
I haven't made anything for dinner yet.
アイルランド料理を作りました。
I made an Irish dish.
これはシェパーズパイといいます。
This is called shepherd's pie.
Shepherd's pie.
Ireland's traditional dish, isn't it?
I've also eaten it in the United States.
Instead of sweet pie, I eat it as rice.
In Ireland, do you usually make shepherd's pie at home?
In Ireland, do people usually make shepherd's pie at home?
ハロウィンに家族でお寿司屋さんに行きました。
Our family went to a sushi restaurant for Halloween.
回転寿司のお店に行きました。
We went to a conveyor belt sushi restaurant.
ハロウィンをテーマにしたお寿司がありました。
They had Halloween-themed sushi.
Tokidoki, iede, osushi wo tsukurimasu.
Sometimes, we make sushi at home.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
Soredewa, minasan, ima gakushu shita hyougen wo tenpo yoku moujito itte mimashou.
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two. Here we go!
Choushoku ni omuretsu wo tsukurimashita.
I made an omelette for breakfast.
昼食にチャーハンを作りました。
I made stir-fried rice for lunch.
デザートにパンプキンパイを焼きました。
I made a pumpkin pie for dessert.
まだ夕食は何も作っていません。
アイルランド料理を作りました。
これはシェパーズパイといいます。
This is called shepherd's pie.
アイルランドでは、普段家でシェパードズパイを作りますか?
In Ireland, do people usually make shepherd's pie at home?
ハロウィンに家族でお寿司屋さんに行きました。
Our family went to a sushi restaurant for Halloween.
回転寿司のお店に行きました。
We went to a conveyor belt sushi restaurant.
ハロウィンをテーマにしたお寿司がありました。
They had Halloween-themed sushi.
Tokidoki iede osushi wo tsukurimasu.
Sometimes we make sushi at home.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
Great job today.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.